克莱斯勒大厦。
The Chrysler building.
>> 克莱斯勒大厦。
>> The Chrysler building.
>> 克莱斯勒。
>> The Chrysler.
这 >> 克莱斯勒。
The >> Chrysler.
>> 克莱斯勒。
>> The Chrysler.
>> 克莱斯勒大厦 >> 陷入麻烦了。
>> The Chrysler building >> is in trouble.
>> 这座历史悠久的摩天大楼正在走向衰败。
>> This venerable skyscraper is falling apart.
它的价值从8亿美元暴跌至1.5亿美元。
Its value has plummeted from $800 million to $150 million.
而且它再次挂牌出售了。
And it's for sale again.
事实上，这是自2019年以来
In fact, this is the third time
该建筑第三次挂牌出售。
the building's been up for sale since 2019.
大楼内部的情况也好不到哪去。
Inside, things aren't much better.
自来水是棕色的，电梯频繁故障，办公室也在慢慢破败。
There's brown tap water, broken elevators, and crumbling offices.
更糟糕的是，纽约一项复杂的土地租约法律
And it's all being made much worse by a complicated New York land leasing law
正在让这栋楼的业主濒临破产。
that's basically bankrupting the building's owner.
这一切都指向一个我实在不想问的问题。
It's all pointing towards a question that I absolutely hate to ask.
克莱斯勒大厦，难道真的要走到尽头了吗？
Could this be the end of the Chrysler building?
好，在正式进入这期视频之前，
Okay, so before we get into this video,
有一件非常重要的事你必须先了解。
there's kind of one really important thing that you need to know.
不管是谁拥有克莱斯勒大厦，他拥有的只是这栋楼，而不是它下面的土地。
Whoever owns the Chrysler building owns the building, but not the land underneath it.
那块土地属于另一个完全不同的人。
That is owned by someone else entirely.
这意味着大楼的业主必须向土地所有者缴纳地租。
It means the owner of the building has to pay rent to the owners of the land.
这使得所有权结构变得极为复杂——而它本来就已经够复杂的了。
Now, that complicates the ownership structure tremendously and it's already very complicated.
那么，克莱斯勒大厦究竟属于谁？
So, who exactly owns the Chrysler building?
答案很可能出乎你的意料。
Well, it's probably not who you think.
你的第一反应大概是：
Your first response would probably be,
"当然是克莱斯勒家族，或者那家汽车公司吧。"
"Well, the Chrysler family, right? Or the car manufacturer."
没错，他们确实曾经拥有过它。
And yes, they did own it once.
这栋大楼最初于1930年由公司创始人沃尔特·克莱斯勒建造并拥有，
It was originally built and owned by the company's founder,
并非由克莱斯勒公司本身所有。
Walter Krysler, in 1930, not by the Krysler Corporation itself.
沃尔特·克莱斯勒希望这座标志性的摩天大楼能作为家族资产传承下去，
Walter Krysler intended the iconic skyscraper to remain a family asset
事实也确实如此，
and it did all the way up until 1953
直到1953年才被开发商威廉·泽肯多夫购入，
when it was purchased by developer William Zeondorf,
这个人是联合国总部背后的推手，
the man behind the UN headquarters
也是五六十年代重塑曼哈顿格局的关键人物。
and the guy responsible for reshaping much of Manhattan during the 50s and 60s.
他想把这栋楼当作一座奖杯。
He wanted the building as a trophy.
此后，在70年代纽约房地产市场的动荡年代，大楼所有权几经易手。
After him, ownership passed through several investors
during the 70s, New York's turbulent real estate era.
最终，到了2008年，它落入了一家阿布扎比投资基金的手中。
Eventually, in 2008, it ended up owned by an Abu Dhabi investment fund.
后来RFR贷款违约，并于2024年进入破产接管。
RFR then defaulted on their loans and went into receiverhip in 2024.
截至2025年，大楼实际上已由RFR的贷款方控制，目前再次处于待售状态。
As of 2025, it's effectively controlled by RFR's lenders, and the building is once again up for sale.
RFR贷款违约的部分原因，
Part of the reason for RFR defaulting on their loans
是土地租金变得极为高昂。
was because the rent for the land became so incredibly expensive.
1902年，在克莱斯勒大厦建造之前，
In 1902, before the Chrysler building
也在我们今天所熟知的纽约大部分地区成形之前，
and before well much of New York as we know it today,
这块地被库珀联盟买下。
this parcel of land was bought by Kooper Union.
库珀联盟是一所私立学院，
Kooper Union was a private college
由实业家兼慈善家彼得·库珀于1859年创办。
founded in 1859 by the industrialist and philanthropist Peter Cooper.
颇具讽刺意味的是，这所学院正是以其建筑和工程学院而闻名。
It was known, ironically, for its schools in architecture and engineering.
购置这块土地，就是为了给学院提供资金来源。
The land was bought as a way to help fund the college.
凭借这一资产和地租收入，
Because of this asset and the rent,
多年来他们收取了数以百万计的美元。
they've been able to collect millions and millions of dollars over the years.
他们也因此得以在很长一段时间内向学生免费提供教育。
They are able or have been able to keep the school free for a long time.
>> 这一土地租约协议在大楼所有权易手时
>> This land leasing agreement continued
得以延续。
when the choir of the building was sold to a new owner.
事实上，不仅延续了下来，租金还大幅上涨。
In fact, not only did it continue, but it increased a lot.
如今，无论谁拥有这栋楼，每年都必须向库珀联盟支付3250万美元，
Today, whoever owns the building has to pay $32.5 million US to Kooper Union annually,
而且这个数字还将继续上涨。
and that number is set to go up.
到2028年将达到4100万美元，
By 2028, it's going to be $41 million,
到2038年则将升至5500万美元。
and by 2038, it'll be 55 million.
最初，克莱斯勒大厦的
Originally, the owner of the Chrysler building
业主主要靠出租办公室获利。
mostly made a profit by leasing out the offices.
但有些出乎意料的是，如今已经没有人想在克莱斯勒大厦里租办公室了。
But perhaps somewhat surprisingly, no one wants an office in the Chrysler building anymore.
至少在它目前的状况下是这样。
at least not in its current state.
所以由于出租率低迷，
So with occupancy low,
业主根本无法收取足够的租金来支付欠库珀联盟的地租。
the owners can't charge enough to cover the rent they owe to Cooper Union.
>> 几十年来，它一直在挂牌和下架之间反复折腾。
>> It's been on and off the market over decades.
我认为这栋楼集中体现了
I think it's a building
纽约房地产市场一切奢靡与颓败的一面。
that encapsulates everything that is decadent and depraved about New York real estate.
它吸引了来自世界各地的全球资本，过去如此，现在依然。
It pulls in and has pulled in global capital from every corner of the world.
它让国内外一些最大的市场参与者深陷困境。
It has been the source of severe distress
这就是一块难啃的硬骨头。
for some of the biggest players in the market both domestically and globally.
It's just a tough asset.
>> 这些摆在眼前的情况已经够令人沮丧的了，
>> All of this is pretty damning
但还有一个更迫切的问题。
as it stands, but there's a more pressing issue still.
克莱斯勒大厦是装饰艺术风格的杰出代表，
The iconic Chrysler building,
而它现在急需大规模修缮。
a standout example of art deco style, needs some serious work.
考虑到它已有近百年历史，
When you consider that it's almost a century old,
这也许并不令人意外。
that perhaps comes as no surprise.
内部据报有棕色自来水、
Internally, there are reports of brown tap water,
电梯频繁故障，以及不达标的电气工程。
lifts breaking down, and electrical work that's not up to par.
纽约的这座"埃菲尔铁塔"正在分崩离析，
New York's Eiffel Tower is falling apart,
却似乎没有人愿意承担责任。
and it feels like no one wants to take responsibility for it.
无论最终是谁买下
Whatever happens,
克莱斯勒大厦，
whoever ends up buying the Chrysler building,
都必须进行一番认真的翻新改造。
some serious renovation work is going to have to take place.
建筑行业有句话：量两次，切一次。
There's a saying in construction, measure twice and cut once.
对于这样一个项目来说，这句话再怎么强调也不为过。
And with a project like this, that could not be more important.
在任何施工开始之前，
Before any construction work can commence,
施工团队必须彻底了解这栋传奇建筑内部的真实状况。
it's vital that construction teams understand exactly what's going on inside this legendary building.
但问题恰恰在这里。
But that's the problem.
我们面对的是近百年前绘制的蓝图，
We're talking about blueprints that were drawn up nearly a century ago
加上几十年来不断叠加的维护记录和改造痕迹。
with decades of maintenance and alterations on top.
而这正是实景捕捉技术发挥关键作用的地方。
But that's where Reality Capture moves the needle.
这也正是颠覆行业的FJD Trion生态系统的用武之地。
And it's exactly how the game-changing FJD Trion ecosystem comes in.
团队无需依赖过时的文档，
Instead of relying on outdated documentation,
只需携带扫描仪走遍现场，捕捉真实的现场状况，
teams can walk the site with a scanner and capture realworld conditions,
让所有人都基于同一份最新的现实数据开展工作。
which means everyone's working from the same up-to-date version of reality.
对于像这样大型、复杂、要求苛刻的项目，
For a project like this,
S2激光雷达扫描仪真的能派上大用场。
large, complex, and demanding, the S2 liar scanner could really save the day.
它能结合建筑所处的周边环境来捕捉建筑外立面，
It can capture the facade of a building in the context of its surroundings,
包括大型和多层建筑环境。
including large scale and multi-level environments.
所有数据都以丰富的细节精准记录，
All of this data is recorded in rich detail
并集成了GNSS用于地理参考定位。
with integrated GNSS for geo reference data.
如果你手头的项目没有克莱斯勒大厦那么复杂，
And if you're working on something a little less challenging than the Chrysler building,
FJD Trion同样有适合你的解决方案。
FJD Trion has got that covered too.
P2激光雷达扫描仪在细节精度和灵活性之间提供了非常出色的平衡。
The P2 LAR scanner offers a really strong balance of detail and flexibility.
或者对于规模较小的项目，
Or for smaller projects,
V4E激光雷达扫描仪为团队提供了一种更简便、更经济实惠的实景捕捉方式，
the V4E lidar scanner gives teams a more straightforward and budget friendly way to capture reality
不会让流程过于复杂。
without over complicating the process.
借助FJD Trion模型，
With the FJD trial model,
扫描数据可以轻松处理成直接融入项目工作流程的成果。
that scan data can be easily processed into outputs that fit directly into project workflows.
甚至还有一键式Revit集成功能，
There's even one-click Revit integration,
让扫描转BIM的过程更加顺畅，大大减少常见的摩擦环节。
which makes scan to BIM much smoother and removes a lot of the usual friction.
你可以扫描屏幕上的二维码，或点击简介中的链接来亲自体验。
You can try it for yourself by scanning the QR code on screen or heading to the link in the description.
这类技术对于历史建筑的保护至关重要。
Technology like this is vital for retaining historic buildings.
在修缮一栋建筑之前，我们必须彻底弄清楚它的运作机理。
Before we can fix a building, we have to understand exactly how it works.
而要做到这一点，
And to do that at the Chrysler building,
就必须从克莱斯勒大厦的诞生说起。
we've got to go all the way back to the beginning.
这是一个带着几分悲剧色彩的故事。
This story is a bit of a tragedy.
克莱斯勒大厦的诞生，与它如今暗淡的现状形成了鲜明反差。
The origins of the Kryer building don't exactly match its less than stellar present.
这座建筑是咆哮的二十年代的骄傲。
This structure was the crown of the roaring 20s.
曼哈顿人满怀期待地看着它在天际线上拔地而起，
Manhattanites watched it soar up their skyline with anticipation,
而它的设计和高度，正是一场激烈竞争的产物。
but its design and height were the result of an intense competition.
这场竞争来自两位昔日商业伙伴兼建筑师——克雷格·塞弗伦斯与威廉·范·阿伦之间的较量。
The rivalry of two business partners, architects Craig Severance and William Van Allen.
塞弗伦斯拿到了曼哈顿公司大楼（即今天的华尔街40号）的设计委托，
Severance landed the commission for the Manhattan Company building known today as 40 Wall Street,
而范·阿伦则受雇设计克莱斯勒大厦。
while Van Allen was hired to design the Chrysler building.
接下来发生的事，早已超越了单纯的商业竞争。
What followed wasn't just business.
这是一场争夺纽约城市天际线制高点的战役。
It was a battle to dominate New York City's skyline.
两位建筑师都在争分夺秒，要建造出世界上最高的建筑。
Both architects were locked in a race to deliver the tallest building on Earth.
随着钢铁结构在下曼哈顿和中城同步攀升，
And as the steel climbed in lower Manhattan and Midtown,
双方都清楚——谁也不愿意输。
it became clear that neither man was willing to lose.
两座高楼同时向上生长，竞争也愈演愈烈。设计图纸遭到泄露。
As both towers rose, the rivalry turned ruthless. Plans were leaked.
施工图被反复研究。
Drawings were scrutinized.
双方都盯着对方的一举一动，拼命寻找超越的机会。
Each side watched the other, desperate for an edge.
华尔街40号大胆而冒险地加盖了额外楼层，
At 40 Wall Street, extra floors were piled on
试图压过曼哈顿的竞争对手。
in a bold and risky bid to try and outdo the building's Manhattan rival.
整个结构已被推到地基所能承受的极限边缘。
The structure was pushed close to the limits of its foundations.
而在短暂的那一刻，它成功了。
And for a brief moment, it worked.
1930年竣工时，华尔街40号成为了世界上最高的建筑。
When it was completed in 1930, 40 Wall Street was the tallest building in the world.
但这一称号只保持了大约一个月，
for about a month
因为在中城的克莱斯勒大厦这边，范·阿伦还藏着最后一招。
because uptown at the Chrysler building, Van Allen had one final move.
隐藏在塔冠内部的，是一根秘密尖顶，被分段秘密组装，从未暴露于外。
Hidden inside the crown was a secret spire assembled in sections out of sight.
就在华尔街40号封顶之后，
Once 40 Wall Street had topped out,
克莱斯勒大厦的尖顶穿过屋顶被吊装到位，
the spire of the Chrysler building was hoisted up through the roof and locked into place,
一举将高度提升了36米。
adding 36 m in a single stroke.
一夜之间，克莱斯勒大厦夺回了王冠。
Overnight, the Krysler building claimed its crown.
但让世人为之倾倒的，远不止它的高度。
But it wasn't just its height that captured the world's imagination.
沃尔特·克莱斯勒要求范·阿伦加入多处与汽车相关的设计元素。
Walter Krysler had asked Van Allen for several carcentric amendments.
外立面上有滴水兽装饰，灵感来自普利茅斯汽车的引擎盖装饰件。
There were gargoyles on the facade inspired by the hood ornaments on the Plymouth.
同样，31层的装饰以克莱斯勒汽车的散热器盖为原型。
Similarly, ornaments on the 31st floor were modeled off Chrysler radiator caps.
还有那顶塔冠——
Then there's the crown,
在过去与现在所有摩天大楼中，从未有过如此独特的设计。
unlike any other crown on any other skyscraper before or since.
标志性的放射状图案，包裹着不锈钢外衣。
The iconic Starburst wrapped in Nora stainless steel.
那些三角形放射状拱门，酷似克莱斯勒那个年代汽车上的轮毂盖。
The triangular radiating arches resemble stylized hub caps from Chrysler cars of the era.
这栋楼保持世界第一高楼的纪录长达339天。
The building was the tallest in the world for 339 days.
之后它被超越，就像在它之前的华尔街40号一样。
It was then eclipsed just like 40 Wall Street before it.
这一次，超越它的是帝国大厦。
This time by the Empire State Building.
如今，克莱斯勒大厦昔日的光彩已有所褪色，这一点毋庸置疑。
Today, it's fair to say
the Chrysler building has lost some of its shine.
周边中城的天际线不断演变，更新更亮眼的写字楼正将租户一一吸走。
The surrounding Midtown skyline has evolved with glossier, larger office buildings drawing tenants away.
曾经的建筑艺术荣耀象征，
Once a symbol of architectural glamour,
如今却深陷办公与零售空置的困境，
the building now suffers from empty office and retail spaces
大量底层空间和大堂区域无人使用，日趋荒废。
with large portions of the ground floor and lobby unoccupied and underused.
租户和访客反映室内设施陈旧、维护问题频出，
Tenants and visitors report outdated interiors, maintenance issues, and a lack of modern amenities,
缺乏现代化配套，使其在与新一代中城写字楼的竞争中明显处于劣势。
making it less competitive with newer Midtown towers.
这是一栋伟大的建筑，但它也需要大量呵护。
This is a great building, but it also needs a lot of love.
它需要大量的改造工作，才能步入21世纪，
Like, it needs a lot of work to be brought into the 21st century
才能与纽约那些如雨后春笋般涌现的新建筑竞争顶级租户。
so that it can compete for A+ tenants with the likes of all these new buildings popping up around New York.
你知道，从外面看它确实美得令人叹为观止，
You know, it's a gorgeous building to look at,
但你真的愿意在这里工作吗？嗯，就目前状况来说，恐怕未必。
but would you want to work here? H maybe right now, not so much.
尽管克莱斯勒大厦拥有遗产建筑认定，也被列为国家历史地标，
Despite its heritage listing and its status as a national historic landmark,
但它实际上并没有获得政府任何历史保护或维护资金。
the Chrysler building doesn't actually receive any funding from the government for historic preservation or maintenance.
这笔费用完全由大楼业主自行承担。
Instead, that bill sits entirely with the building's owner.
而考虑到这栋楼需要大量维护，
And given that this building needs quite a lot of upkeep,
这笔开销可不是小数目。
that bill isn't small.
大堂天花板已经破损，经常用胶带勉强维持。
There's the deteriorated lobby ceiling, which is often times covered in tape.
旋转门频繁卡壳。
The revolving doors regularly jam.
电梯容易出故障，甚至还有老鼠和其他害虫侵扰的报告。
The lifts are prone to malfunctioning and there are even reports of mice and other infestations.
尽管老鼠在大城市的任何建筑里都是常见问题，
While mice are a common problem for any building in a big city,
但持续的虫害防治难题多少说明在密封和日常维护方面存在漏洞。
ongoing pest control challenges kind of point to gaps in modern ceiling and maintenance.
但更大的问题还是出在外立面上。
But much of the bigger issues are to do with the exterior.
那根标志性的、曾经夺得世界之冠的尖顶正在漏水，急需修缮。
That iconic record stealing spire is leaking and in desperate need of restoration.
原始的1930年代钢框架窗户和砖石外墙漏风，
The original 1930s steel framed windows and masonry walls leak air
隔热性能之差也在意料之中。
and unsurprisingly are pretty poorly insulated.
我前面几次提到了棕色自来水的问题，
I mentioned those reports of brown water a couple of times earlier
这很可能是管道腐蚀或供水系统故障造成的。
and that's probably due to corrosion or supply issues.
问题在于，
The question becomes,
克莱斯勒大厦现在是否还是一个世界级的场所，值得顶级租户支付顶级租金？
is the Chrysler building a worldass place where a top tier tenant would pay top dollar?
而答案，眼下绝对是否定的。
And the answer at the moment is absolutely not.
所以任何打算入手的新业主，不仅要接手财务上的烂摊子，
So any new owner that's coming in
还得耗费心力对大楼进行全面升级，
has to also kind of sign up for both the financial and brain damage cost of upgrading the building
让它步入21世纪。
and bringing it into the 21st century.
据估计，这将是一个耗资1.5亿到2亿美元的项目，
And their estimate is this is going
才能让这栋楼重新达标。
to be a 150 to $200 million job to get this building up to snuff.
由于这栋楼被列为地标，
Because the building is landmarked,
任何外部或内部改动都需要获得纽约市地标保护委员会的批准。
any exterior or interior changes require approval from the city's landmarks preservation commission.
好，在今天的视频继续之前，
Now, before we go any further with today's video,
我需要先暂停一下，
we need to stop everything
因为我有一个重大消息终于可以公开了。
because I have got some very big news that I am finally allowed to share.
去年，企鹅兰登书屋问我是否有兴趣写一本书。
Last year, Penguin Random House asked me if I'd like to write a book.
我答应了。
I said yes.
我写了一本书，就是这本。
I've written a book and here it is.
书名叫《超级工程：将改变我们世界的10个超级建设项目》。
It is called Mega Builds: 10 Colossal Construction Projects that will change our world.
过去10年里，
Over the last 10 years,
我近距离亲历了这个星球上一些最不可思议的建设项目，
I have had a front row seat some of this planet's most incredible construction projects,
它们全都收录在这本书里。
and they are all in here.
我把它们都写下来了。
I've written about them.
我深入的程度，超过了
I've gone deeper than I've ever gone before
我在任何视频、故事或长篇纪录片中所达到的深度。
in any video story or any kind of like long form documentary.
这是幕后的故事。
This is behind the scenes.
这是近距离的、个人化的记录。书中有一线团队的故事。
It's up close and personal. It meets the teams.
有那些真实的人情味。
It's the human stories.
有详细的工程细节。
It's the engineering in detail.
也有我的亲身经历，
It's my personal experiences
以及近距离接触这些项目时所遭遇的种种状况。
and some of the calamities I've had along the way getting up close with these projects.
写这本书，我真的非常享受。
I have really enjoyed writing this.
我有几个朋友说：
Some of my mates have been like,
"哦，不错啊。那个……谁帮你捉刀的？"
"Oh, nice. Who uh who ghost wrote that for you?"
没有任何人。
No one.
我请不起什么大牌捉刀手。就是我自己写的。
I can't afford a fancy ghost writer. Me. I wrote this.
每一个字，都是从我脑子里流淌进笔记本电脑，
Every single word of this has come from my head
再进入这本书的。
into my laptop and then into this book.
全部都是为了让你阅读欣赏。
All for your reading pleasure.
朋友们，我以前从没想过自己能写一本书，但我做到了。
Guys, I never thought I could write a book, but I have.
显然，我是有所偏颇的，但我真的觉得这本书还挺不错的。
And obviously, I'm biased, but I actually kind of think it's quite good.
现在可以预订了，链接在下方。
It is available to pre-order now. The link is below.
预订非常重要。
Pre-ordering is incredibly important.
基本上，我整个未来的幸福都取决于你预订这本书。
Basically, my entire future happiness depends on you pre-ordering this book.
所以，朋友们，如果你喜欢B1M，如果你喜欢这些故事，
So guys, if you love the B1M, if you love these stories,
如果你喜欢以简单易懂、
if you love learning more about construction in a downto-earth way that's easy to understand
接地气的方式了解建筑工程，那就去预订我的书《超级工程》吧，就是现在。
and can be read by anyone, go and pre-order my book, Mega Builds, today.
那么，哪里有将老旧标志性建筑改造成现代化场所的成功经验呢？
So, where is there some experience of retrofitting
old iconic buildings to suit the modern day?
让我们把目光投向一座到处都是大型历史建筑的城市。
Well, let's look to a city absolutely jam-packed with huge historic buildings.
伦敦。
London.
近年来最著名的案例之一，是巴特西发电站。
One of the most famous examples in recent times is Batsy Power Station.
你可能在平克·弗洛伊德的专辑《Animals》封面上
You might recognize it from the cover of Pink Floyd's Animals
见过它，也可能是在《蝙蝠侠：黑暗骑士》里它作为废墟出现的场景。
or when it was used as wreckage in the Dark Knight.
对许多伦敦人来说最熟悉的是后者，
It's the last part that many Londoners are going to be familiar with
因为在21世纪的大半时间里，这座标志性建筑——欧洲最大的砖结构建筑——
because for the better part of the 21st century, this iconic building, the largest brick building in all of Europe,
一直处于废弃状态。
was left abandoned.
巴特西发电站之所以没有被拆除，
Battery power station wasn't demolished
很大程度上是因为它于1980年获得了二级保护建筑的身份。
largely because it was granted grade 2 listed status in 1980.
这一法律保护意味着修缮，而非拆除。
That legal protection meant restoration.
作为伦敦最具标志性的工业地标之一，它的文化意义最终保住了它的未来。
As one of London's most recognizable industrial landmarks, its cultural significance ultimately secured its future.
即便历经数十年的废弃和一系列失败的改造方案，
Even after decades of dereliction and a string of failed schemes
通过转型为综合用途目的地，
by becoming a mixeduse destination,
这座发电站最终实现了自我养活。
the power station was able to fund its own survival.
如今，它已成为这座城市一处充满活力的热门场所。
Today, it's a thriving hot spot for this city.
但距克莱斯勒大厦更近的地方，也有更贴切的案例。
But there are even more apt examples not far from the Chrysler building itself.
熨斗大厦于1902年作为办公楼首次建成，
The Flat Iron Building, first completed in 1902 as an office structure,
目前正在被改造成住宅公寓，
is currently being retrofitted into residential apartments
开发商围绕这个著名的三角形平面展开设计。
with developers working around the famous triangular floor plan.
此外众所周知，伍尔沃斯大厦——也曾一度是世界最高建筑——
Notoriously, the Walworth building, which was also once the tallest building in the world,
将其顶层改造成了豪华顶层公寓，
converted its top floors into a luxury penthouse
最终以1.1亿美元成交。
and then sold that for $110 million.
这比美国普通住宅中位价高出好几百倍。
That's more than a few hundred times the US median home price.
这个价格当然令人咋舌，
It's an insane price tag,
但如果套用到克莱斯勒大厦上，这笔钱肯定能大大缓解它的财务困境。
but one that would certainly go a very long way to helping fix the Chrysler building's financial wos.
试想，住在世界上最著名的塔冠里会是什么感觉。
Imagine living inside the most famous crown in the world.
伍尔沃斯大厦对顶层进行了著名的改建公寓，
So, the Woolworth building famously underwent a condo conversion on the top floors,
但那次改建简直是一场彻底的灾难。
but it's been a complete disaster of a condo conversion.
不过，也有一些看起来更有希望的案例。
There have been others that are seemingly more promising.
熨斗大厦，同样是一栋标志性建筑，
The Flat Iron Building, again, another iconic building,
与纽约天际线早已融为一体，正在被改建成精品公寓。
so synonymous with the New York skyline, that is being converted to boutique condos.
目前来看，销售情况相当不错。
And so far, sales have been have been pretty promising.
这是一个我们将越来越频繁面对的问题。
This is a problem we're going to see a lot more of.
历史上头一次，我们面对的是已有百年历史的摩天大楼，
For the first time in history, we're seeing century old skyscrapers,
而我们不能简单地把它们拆掉。
and we can't just tear them down.
首先，拆除这些建筑本身就极为困难。
First off, it would be tremendously difficult to knock down any of these buildings.
这些最早期的摩天大楼之所以被过度设计，是因为在此之前从来没有建过这么高的建筑。
These first skyscrapers were overengineered because nothing had been built that tall before.
它们拥有极为庞大的钢铁骨架，
They have immense steel skeletons
并以砖石和不锈钢包覆，以应对极端的耐久性需求。
and they're clad in brick, stone, and stainless steel for intense durability.
其次，像克莱斯勒大厦这样的摩天大楼受到法律保护。
Secondly, skyscrapers like the Chrysler building are protected.
即便有人想在原址上建造更高、可销售面积更大的建筑，
Even if there is a temptation to build something taller with more sellable space,
也只有在原建筑破损到无法修复的程度时才有可能实现。
that can only happen if the building went beyond repair.
更有可能的结果是，
It's probably more likely
内部会像巴特西发电站或伍尔沃斯大厦那样
that the interior is going to be retrofitted
进行改造升级。
like Battery Power Station or the Walworth building.
>> 我们确实看到中城部分区域出现了大量办公转住宅的案例，对吧？
>> We've certainly seen a flurry of office to residential conversions in parts of Midtown, right?
我们在整个曼哈顿写字楼市场都看到了这一点，
We've seen that all over
写字楼市场现在正处于黄金时代。
the Manhattan office market is in a golden era right now.
净吸纳量——
Net absorption,
即实际成交的净租赁面积——
which means the net amount of space that was leased
处于近四分之一个世纪以来的最高水平。
is at the highest it's been in a quarter century.
>> 这意味着，写字楼市场正在回暖，尤其是在中城。
>> It means the office is back, especially in Midtown.
也许克莱斯勒大厦所需要的，只是一点点爱。
Maybe all the cries the building needs is a little love.
>> 当然，你可以做一些事情，比如引入顶级餐饮品牌，
>> Now, there are certainly things you could do like put in top tier restaurant concepts,
也许在零售广场上做一些真正有创意的尝试，
maybe do some really innovative things with the retail plaza
具体取决于买家是谁，以及他们手上有什么资源。
depending on who the buyer is and what they have access to.
但如果你把它当作写字楼来运营，这件事还是可以做成的。
But if you run it as office, you can still make this work.
但这可是克莱斯勒大厦啊。我是说，它还是有相当的品牌魅力的。
But this is the freaking Chrysler building. I mean, this still has cache.
你完全可以想象，
This is you can imagine
某家顶级对冲基金、某个金融机构，
a top tier hedge fund or a financial institution of some kind
甚至是某家科技公司，说："我的办公室在克莱斯勒大厦。"
or even a tech company saying hey you know what my offices are at the Chrysler building.
>> 那么，现在到底是什么情况？
>> So what's happening now?
大厦的前业主之一、开发商铁狮门正在重新考虑接手。
One of the building's former owners developer Tishman Spayer is eyeing it up again.
他们于1997年首次以2.2亿美元的价格获得所有权，
They first took ownership in 1997 for a cool $220 million
并在2000年主持了最近一次翻新改造。
and undertook its most recent renovation in 2000.
当时，这家房地产投资公司斥资1亿美元，
Back then, the real estate investment company spent a hundred million
精心修复了这座摩天大楼的装饰艺术风格元素，
carefully restoring the skyscrapers art deco motifs
同时对核心系统进行了升级。
while upgrading its core systems.
铁狮门是九十年代末期的买家之一，也是业主之一，
Tishman Spire, who was one of the one of the buyers or one of the owners in the late '9s,
他们把阿布扎比引入进来，
actually brought Abu Dhabi in,
此后作为托管人和共同业主一直参与其中，直到不久之前。
stayed on as custodian and part owner of the building until very recently.
据传他们又重新加入了竞购行列，如果他们买下来，那将会非常有意思。
They're rumored to be back in the mix here, and if they buy it, it'll be really interesting.
克莱斯勒大厦最终或许会与另一座纽约地标走向相似的命运，
The Chrysler building could end up with the same fate as a certain other New York icon,
有趣的是，那座建筑正面临几乎一模一样的困境。
but funnily enough is facing almost exactly the same struggle.
>> 杰夫·盖尔近来在拍卖会上买下了熨斗大厦，
>> Jeff Gell prominently is the one who recently bought the Flat Iron building at auction
目前正在将其改建成豪华公寓，引发了广泛关注。
and is now turning it into into luxury condos.
而另一个关键细节是，
And the other wrinkle here is that
杰夫·盖尔长期以来都是库珀联盟的董事会成员。
Jeff Gell for a long time was on the board of Cooper Union.
所以他与卖方，以及最终的地主，都有着非常深厚的关系。
So pretty well connected to the seller and eventual landlord as well.
>> 克莱斯勒大厦能否重归九十年代的业主手中，
>> The return of the Chrysler building to its '90s owners
如今完全取决于围绕其与库珀联盟那份巨额土地租约的
now entirely depends on negotiations surrounding its enormous land leasing agreement
谈判结果。
with Kooper Union.
目前这栋楼的空置率在14%到20%之间。
The building currently has a vacancy rate between 14 and 20%.
显然，某些方面必须做出让步。
So it's clear something is going to have to give.
克莱斯勒大厦如今站在了十字路口。
The Chrysler building now stands at a crossroads.
它提醒着我们，曾经有一个年代，
It's a reminder of an era
美国建造一栋楼，追求的不只是利润，更是荣耀。
when America built not just for profit but for prestige.
但它的价值远不止于此，还有某种难以言说的东西。
But its value is something even more than that. Something intangible.
我相信，当你看着它时，你也有和我一样的感受。
And I know you probably feel the same thing
as I do when you look at it.
这不只是一栋建筑。
This isn't just a building.
它远不止是一栋建筑。
It's much more than a building.
它是一件真正滋养灵魂的建筑艺术品。
It's a piece of architecture that really feeds the soul.
问题在于，在当今这个时代，
The problem is in today's day and age,
在当今的纽约，一切都似乎只看底线。
in today's New York, it feels like everything has a bottom line.
本视频由FJD Trion生态系统赞助。
This video was sponsored by the FJD Trion ecosystem.
别忘了，
Don't forget that
如果你想自己将真实世界的环境转化为数字模型，
if you want to turn real world environments into digital models for yourself,
可以点击下方链接，体验FJD Trion生态系统。
you can try out the FJD Tron ecosystem at the link below.
一如既往，
And as always guys,
朋友们，如果你喜欢这期视频，
if you enjoyed this video
想要从这个建筑工程权威频道获取更多内容，记得订阅B1M。
and you want to get more from the definitive video channel for construction, make sure you subscribe to the B1M.